Register of the Mark Sullivan Papers, 1883-1952
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1883-1952
  - Wright, S. G., 1934
  - Wright, Z. E., 1938
  - Wyeth, Mrs. George A., 1934-36
  - Wynne, Peter, 1943
  - Wysor, Davidson Charlton, 1941-45
  - Yeandle, S. S., 1924
  - Yolland, Edgar H., 1940
  - Young, E. Narshall, 1919
  - Young, J. Arthur, 1935
  - Young, James R., 1941
  - Young, Lafayette, 1920-26
  - Youngquist, Gustaf A., 1931
  - Youngren, J. A., 1935
  - Zihlman, Frederick N., 1920
  - Zimmerman, Robert W., 1935
  - Zolenge, Beatrice, 1938
  - Zuccaro, Joseph, 1934
  - Zuckerman, H. G., 1935
  - Miscellaneous
- SUBJECT FILE, 1888-1952
  - Agriculture, 1926-42 (Box 21.)
  - Allen, Ben, 1936
  - Allen, Henry, n.d.
  - American Jewish Congress, 1923
  - American Newspaper Guild, 1942
  - Anti-Lynching bill, 1937
  - Atomic energy, n.d.
  - Baker, Newton D., 1917
  - Baker, Ray Stannard, Woodrow Wilson and World Settlement. Galleys.
    - Volume I-II, n.d.
    - Volume III, n.d.
  - Banking, 1939 (Box 22.)
  - Barnard College, 1939
  - Baruch, Bernard, M., 1920
  - Biographical file, 1899-50
    - General
    - Agreements and contracts, 1920-30
    - Cartoon of Mark Sullivan at work, n.d.
    - West Chester State Normal School, 1888-92
    - Harvard, 1900-03
    - Family background, 1920
    - Honors and awards, 1903-50
    - Invitations, press cards, appointments, introductions, 1909-21 (Box 23.)
    - Marriage, 1907
    - Personal business file, 1905-57
    - Publicity, 1920-50
  - Black Lobby Committee, 1936
  - Boettinger, John, 1939
  - Bok, Edward W., 1923
  - Booking publishing, 1939
  - Boone, Joel T., n.d.
  - Boulder Dam, 1929
  - Bourne, Jonathan Jr., 1919
  - Broun, Heywood, 1939
  - Cullhan, P. H., 1924
  - Clapper, Raymond, n.d.
  - Clarkson, Grosvenor, 1920
  - Collier's Weekly, 1912
  - Colt, Senator, 1920
  - Communism, 1930-40
  - Coolidge, Calvin, 1931 (Box 24.)
  - Couzens, James, 1933
  - Cravath, Paul D., 1922
  - Cresson, W. P., 1930
  - Crowther, Samuel, Life of George W. Perkins. Unpublished biography (typewritten carbon copy), 1907.
  - Daniels, Josephus, 1925
  - Darling, J.N. (Ding), 1931
  - Davis, Charles, 1930
  - Dies Committee
  - Dolliver, Jonathan P., n.d.
  - Economic chronology, 1929-39
  - Electrical College, 1924
  - Electric light and power industry, U.S., 1937
  - Evolution, n.d.
  - Federal Trade Commission, n.d.
  - Fonseca, Annibal Freirda, 1928
  - Freedom of the press, 1941
  - Fuller, Gaylord M., 1926
  - Germany, 1944
  - Gignilliat, Brigadier General L.R., 1923
  - Gold stabilization fund, 1936-44
  - Government agencies (executive branch)
    - Agricultural Adjustment Administration, 1934
    - Federal Emergency Relief Administration, 1934
    - National Labor Relations Board, 1939 (Box 25.)
    - National Recovery Administration, 1933
    - National Recovery Administration, 1933-35 (Box 26.)
    - National Youth Administration, 1942
    - Works Progress Administration, 1937
  - Great Britain, 1919
  - Harding, Mrs. Warren G., 1921
  - Harvey, W. H., 1923
  - Hatch Act, n.d.
  - Hays, William H., 1921
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1927-34
    - General
    - Banking Crisis, 1933 (Box 27.)
  - Hughes, Charles Evans, 1916
  - Hunt, J. N., n.d.
  - Industrial chemistry, 1941
  - Installment buying, 1939
  - International Conference of Medical Women, 1919
  - Irwin, Will, 1928
  - Japan, 1940
  - Johnson, Hugh S., 1929
  - Kennan, George, n.d.
  - Koppel, Howard, interviews with laborers, n.d.
  - Ku-Klux Klan, 1921
  - Labor, 1933-45
  - Labor, 1933-45 (Box 28.)
  - Law enforcement, 1929-30 (Box 29.)
  - Leacock, Stephen, Disarmament and Common Sense Galleys, n.d., Printed copy.
  - League of Nations, 1915
  - Lend-Lease bill, 1943-47
  - Lewis, John L., 1943
  - Lindburgh, Charles, 1939-41
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1936
  - Litrinor, M., 1928 (Box 30.)
  - Luce, Clare Booth, 1941-44
  - MacArthur, Douglas, 1942-44
  - McCormick, Medill, 1923
  - MacFarland, Peter Clark, 1913
  - McGuffy, William H., 1928
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1945
  - McNary, Charles L., 1940
  - McNutt, Paul V., 1940
  - Maculay, Thomas B., n.d.
  - Manpower, 1942
  - Marcantonio, Vito, 1944
  - Marshall, George C., n.d.
  - Matthews, J. B., 1943
  - Mead bill, n.d.
  - Mellett, Lowell, n.d.
  - Mercantile marine, n.d.
  - Mexico, 1939-40
  - Miller, Harlan, n.d.
  - Miller, A. C., The Banking Bill, 1935.
  - Miscellany
  - Moley, Raymond, 1940
  - Molotoff, V., 1939
  - Monetary policy and price control, 1930-41 (Box 31.)
  - Monopoly and anti-trust, 1940
  - Monroe Doctrine, 1940
  - Mooney, Thomas J., 1942
  - Muscle Shoals, 1927
  - Myers, William Starr, The Origins of the Banking Panic of March 4, 1933, June 8, 1935.
  - National debt, 1940
  - National defense, 1939
  - National Nonpartisan League, n.d.
  - National Socialism, 1939
  - Neutrality, 1939-41 (Box 32.)
  - New Deal, 1934
  - New Deal, 1934 (Box 33.)
  - Northcliffe (Lord), 1917
  - Palestine, 1943
  - Patterson, Joseph M., n.d.
  - Patterson, Robert, n.d.
  - Patton, George, 1943
  - Peace plans, 1943
  - Pearl Harbor, 1942
  - Pearson, Drew, 1943
  - Pecora, Ferdinand, 1938
  - Pegler, Westbrook, 1942-43
  - Pennsylvania Dutch, 1939
  - Perkins, Milo
  - Pershing, John J., 1918
  - Pew, Joseph N., n.d.
  - Philadelphia Record, n.d.
  - Pinchot, Amos, 1918 (Box 34.)
  - Plunkett, Sir Horace, n.d.
  - PM, 1943
  - Poetry and literature, n.d.
  - Poland, 1944-45
  - Politics, 1928
  - Pope Piux XII, 1939
  - Popular music, 1927
  - Population trends, 1920
  - Postwar problems, 1942-43
  - Power of the presidency, 1943
  - Potato control, 1935
  - Presidential election of 1936
  - Presidential election of 1940 (Box 35.)
  - Prohibition, 1932
  - Propaganda, examples and techniques, 1934
  - Property seizure bill, n.d.
  - Public utilities, 1930-31 (Box 36.)
  - Race relations, 1944-45
  - Race relations (Box 37.)
  - Reapportionment, 1929
  - Roosevelt, Franklin, 1938-1941
  - Roosevelt, Theodore
    - General
    - Letter from R. J. Collier
    - Memorial Association, 1927
    - Military, 1910
  - Root, Elihu, 1920
  - Saturday Review of Literature, n.d.
  - School of International Studies, University of Virginia, n.d.
  - Selective Service, 1917-42
  - Shargo, John, n.d.
  - Sherwood, Robert E., 1942
  - Silver, 1930-31 (Box 38.)
  - Smith, Al, 1923
  - Social planning, n.d.
  - Social Security, 1939
  - Socialized medicine, 1944
  - South, the n.d.
  - Soviet Union, 1933
  - Stockton, Gilchrist, B., 1928
  - Supreme Court, 1937
  - Swing, Raymond Gram, n.d.
  - Taft, William H., 1919
  - Tariff, 1935
  - Taxation, 1936
  - Technocracy, 1933
  - Television, 1939
  - Theatre, 1939
  - Third term issue, 1928,1940
  - Townsend plan, 1934 (Box 39.)
  - Treaty of peace with Germany following World War I, 1919
  - Tumulty, Joseph P., n.d.
  - Unemployment, 1928
  - United Nations, 1944
  - U.S. budget, 1917
  - U.S. Shipping Board Emergency Fleet Corporation, 1920
  - Veterans, 1932
  - Voting, 1943
  - Wallace, Henry A., n.d.
  - Walter-Logan bill, 1940
  - War referendum issue, 1939
  - White, William Allen, news releases by, 1919
  - Willis, H. Park, 1935
  - Wilson, Woodrow, July 4, 1918
- WRITINGS, 1912-1951
  - Newspaper column, clippings (Box 40.)
    - 1923-26
    - 1927-29 (Box 41.)
    - 1930-32 (Box 42.)
    - 1933-34 (Box 43.)
    - 1936-38 (Box 44.)
    - 1939-42 (Box 45.)
    - 1943-46 (Box 46.)
    - 1947-51 (Box 47.)
  - Titled writings (Box 48.)
    - A.A.A. (Agriculture [UNK] Administration) Crack Down on Wheat Seen as [UNK] Get Quota-Cards, a typewritten draft, May 22, 1936.
    - America's Delegates to the Conference, a printed article in World's Works, December 1921.
    - Are You a Good Listener? a printed article in Women's Day, November, [UNK].
    - Back to America, a typewritten draft, 1919.
    - Back to Truth, a typewritten and handwritten draft, n.d.
    - Brain Trust to Curb Inventions Declared Inviting New Revolt, a typewritten draft, n.d.
    - The Biggest Year in History, handwritten and typewritten drafts printed in Hearst's International Cosmopolitan, 1939.
    - Churchill-Greatness in Our Time, a printed article in Reader's Digest, 1945.
    - Collectivism Declared Aim of Administration, a printed article fromthe Washington Star, 1934.
    - Comment on Congress, a printed article from Collier's Weekly, n.d.
    - Economic Royalist Among Men: Grows Plump by Own Ingenuity, a typewritten draft, n.d.
    - England Must Win Or Else, a printed article in Reader's Digest,, 1940.
    - An Episode in the Life of Mr. Magee, a handwritten draft, n.d.
    - The Federal Reserve Board, typewritten and handwritten drafts, n.d., Photocopy.
    - The History that Will Do Justice to President Hoover, a typewritten draft, n.d. (Box 49.)
    - Hoover's Great Achievement, a printed article in the New York Herald-Tribune, n.d.
    - If Crop Reduction is Beneficial Why Fight the Japanese Beetle, a typewritten draft, 1936.
    - If I Need Relaxation, a printed article in Reader's Digest and Scribner's Commentator, November 1, 1938.
    - The Man Who Done It, a reprinted article from Collier's Weekly, August 3, 1912.
    - Mark Sullivan's Letter, a printed clipping from the New York Herald-Tribune, 1942.
    - Migration of Farm Boys to City Adds to Economic Commotion, a typewritten draft, July 18, 1936.
    - New Invation of Farm Privacy Seen in A.A.A. Sky Snoopers, a typewritten draft, June 20, 1936.
    - New World, a printed article in Collier's Weekly, October 18, 1919.
    - Nosy Primitive `New Deal' [UNK] for Skunk's Bad Name, a typewritten draft, n.d.
    - Not Hymn Books but Bank Books, a printed article in Collier's Weekly, October 29, 1921.
    - October in the County Pictures as Compared to Nervous Cities, a typewritten draft, October 5, 1936.
    - Orgy a printed article in Hearst's International Cosmopolitan. October, 1933.
    - OUR TIMES, VOlumes I-VI, 1924-1935. Handwritten and typewritten drafts.
      - Volume I, chapters 1-12, 14
      - Volume II, chapter 10
      - Volume III, chapters 3 and 7 (Box 50.)
      - Volume IV, chapters 1-7
      - Volume V, chapter 20, part of chapter 23
      - Volume VI, part of chapters 1-3, chapters 4-12 (complete)
      - Volume VI, chapters 14-17 (complete) (Box 51)
      - Volume VII (proposed)
      - Volume VII (proposed) (Box 52.)
    - Parable Drawn from Life of Pheasant, Hemmed in by Foes, a printed clipping from the New York Herald-Tribune, 1942. (Box 53.)
    - The Patent Medicine Conspiracy against the Freedom of the Press, a printed article with typewritten and handwritten drafts for Collier's Weekly, 1905
    - Pennsylvania Sow Produces Abundance Without U.S. Aid, a typewritten draft, n.d.
    - Petrillo Calls the Tune, a typewritten draft, n.d.
    - Policy of Friendliness Brings Deer Back to Chester County, Pa., a typewritten draft, 1936.
    - Politics, in 1928,: a printed article in the New York Herald-Tribune, n.d.
    - Pool-Room Evil, a printed article in the Outlook, May 28,1904.
    - The President's Job, a printed article from Liberty, April 17, 1943.
    - Programs and Personalities on the Air, a typewritten draft, n.d.
    - Realization in Washington, a printed article from the American Bankers Association Journal, May 1934.
    - Review of 1935, a typewritten (carbon copy) draft, 1935.
    - Review of Old Favorites, a typewritten draft for McGuffey Readers, 1936.
    - Review of Twenty-five Years, a printed article in Nation's Business, 1937.
    - Roosevelt As I See Him, a typewritten draft for Liberty, October 3, 1942.
    - Roosevelt Urges to Set Terms to his Potatoe-Raising Challange, a typewritten draft, March 18, 1938.
    - Skunk's Host Hears Animal Will Leave If It Gets a Letter, a typewritten draft, February 28, 1938.
    - Supreme Court As It Is Today,: a printed article in the Congressional Digest, 1933. (Box 54.)
    - III. Congressionale, a printed article from the American Bankers Association Journal, November 1933.
    - Wake Up America! printed article in the New York Herald-Tribune, November 17, 1935.
    - When America Work, a printed article for Collier's Weekly, April 6, 1918. Handwritten draft accompanies.
    - Where Are the Promises Men Live By? a printed article in Reader's Digest, 1939.
    - Who'll Get the Big Job? a printed article in Collier's Weekly, January 1, 1927.
    - Who'll Ride the Donkey? a printed article in Collier's Weekly, March 5, 1927.
  - Subject file of untitled drafts and articles
    - Advancement of medicine since 1900
    - Harding, Warren G., 1921-23
    - Hoover, Herbert C., 1929-33
    - Japanese-American relations, n.d. (Box 55.)
    - Lane, Frank, 1912
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1941
    - Mellon, Andrew, 1924
    - Miscellany
    - Miscellany (Box 56.)
    - Presidential elections of 1912 (Box 57.)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1933-45
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1907 (Box 58.)
    - Steinbeck, John, 1941
    - Wilson, Woodrow, 1913-21
    - World War I, 1917-1918
    - World War I (post), 1919
    - 1919-1929
    - World War II, 1939-1945
- SPEECHES AND BROADCASTS, 1939-1942.
  - America Seen in Conflict Between Two Social Ideas, n.d. Printed commencement address at Lehigh University, Bethleham, Pennsylvania, New York Herald-Tribune. (Box 59.)
  - The Choice Before Us, n.d. A printed address delivered to the Rotary International Convention Delegates.
  - The Day of Decision, June 6, 1936. A commencement exercise address given at Washington and Jefferson College, Washington, Pennsylvania.
  - Founder's Night Address, December 31, 1939. A speech delivered in Gramercy Park, Washington, D. C. Printed in The Player's Bulletin, March 1, 1940.
  - The Heinz Cavalcade. A weekly broadcast based primarily on Our Times, n.d. Typewritten (carbon copy) draft of a broadcast from the Turn of the Century (Our Times, Volume I). (Box 60.)
  - The Mark Sullivan and Jay Franklin Debates, NBC, December 1938-August 1939. Typewritten drafts of debates.
  - Miscellany (Box 61.)
  - We the People, December 1942. Typewritten draft of broadcast.
  - Miscellany (Box 62.)
    - Memorabilia
      - 2 commemorative keys
    - Notebooks
    - Oversize material
      - 3 albums of newspaper clippings and letters of condolence, concerning the death of Mark Sullivan, 1952 & albums of newspaper clippings, 1922-52